<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title> on Blog </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/tags/cloud/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Gaming Social Network</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Gaming-Social-Network/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Gaming-Social-Network/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cloud Gaming Social Network refers to 3 terms i.e. Online Gaming, Social Network and Cloud Computing. It refers to building a platform wherein users can play any type of game online and pay as per usage. It will have a built-in social network wherein users can connect with fellow-players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It innovates the Gaming Social Network which would host all games ranging from flash games to arcade games and reaching upto high end games based on Cloud &amp;amp; Virtualization Technology.
Since Social Network, Online Gaming &amp;amp; Cloud Computing are hot trending technologies. Combining all these new technologies would lead to a whole new area of opportunities for employment and research in this new sector of gaming. It would enable people to play any game for free, just requiring an internet connection of minimum specified bandwidth required for the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sector uses many computer technologies in order to enhance its output and Cloud Computing is the technology which can blur up the line between real and virtual world.
The main objective is to enable people to play any game for free by just requiring an internet connection which would include support for multiplayer games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problems faced by Customers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solving the following issues faced by customers in the Gaming Sector:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Purchasing games is a costly affair.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Requirements specified for every games.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Privacy is High.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cost of Upgradation is high.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Need of buying games for different people in order to play in multiplayer mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solutions of Customers Problem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free from privacy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seamless meeting of people with similar preferences of games.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to play multiplayer games with people across the world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No need of upgrading the hardware to play any game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No need of downloading any game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce use of torrents for downloading premium games for free.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can emulate PC games to optimize it for playing high end games from a console such as Smartphones etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What other Benefits&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collaborating people to form a circle of friends across the globe having similar preferences of games.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy accessibility of all types of games in a simple customized UI for the gamers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No specifications required for playing any type of games, just requiring an internet connection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gamers can access and play all the genres of games for free by just requiring Internet Connection without the need of even thinking about minimal specification required in running of a game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gamers can collaborate to form a community within a circle and groups in social network to get along with gamers having interest in same games.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The future scope is emulating PC games to optimize it for playing high end games from a console such as Smartphones, XBOX 360, Play Station 3 etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Piracy will be reduced upto 200 %.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Computing Future Trends</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Computing-Future-Trends/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Computing-Future-Trends/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The rise of the hybrid cloud&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hybrid clouds feature an infrastructure that combines private cloud security with cost-effective, powerful and scalable public cloud attributes.
IT executives get more choices for personalized solutions while big data advocates and security experts are still satisfied.
As hybrid models become mainstream, more companies are likely to adopt this cloud deployment model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Big data Analytics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many organizations are realizing that it may be much simpler and more beneficial to combine big data analytics with cloud computing than to choose one over the other&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Big data as a service&lt;/strong&gt; seems like one of the most practical options for big data analytics, as it is scalable and within the reach of any organisation, no matter its size or resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These cloud providers are also overcoming the technical barrier by transforming Hadoop from an open source platform to an enterprise-ready service, all without the need for a data scientist. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Graphics as a Service&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically, running high-end graphics applications requires substantial hardware infrastructure investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, cloud computing is changing this reality. There are a number of new cloud-based graphics technologies from prominent graphics companies, including NVIDIA and AMD that allow end users to run high-end graphic design applications with a simple HTML5 web browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identity Management and Protection&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security has always been a major concern with cloud computing. As more businesses move more information and data into cloud servers, this concern is more important than ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is anticipated that over the few years, there will be identity management solutions based on new cloud based security paradigms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web-Powered Apps&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As efficiency and scalability are among the primary benefits of cloud computing, then it only makes sense to start developing cloud-based applications that are compatible with multiple platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standardization will take center-stage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cloud ecosystem today is characterized by a plethora of standards, mostly unique to service providers and therefore incompatible with other platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently more than 160 different standards govern cloud computing systems. This situation has the potential to dampen the growth prospects of the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shift towards common or open standards for cloud deployments will be central to the development of the cloud model, especially if features like interoperability and portability are to be realized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consortiums like the Open Data Center Alliance (ODCA), framed to focus attention on the crying need for a dependable framework to progress the evolution of organizational standards, that streamline the cloud journey, will grow in stature.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Computing Forecast</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Computing-Forecast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Computing-Forecast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public cloud market overall will grow 18.5 percent, to $131 billion, in 2017 from $111 billion in 2012.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By 2018, IDC forecasts that public cloud spending will more than double to $147.5 billion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Global SaaS software revenues are forecasted to reach $106B in 2017, increasing 21% over projected 2016 spending levels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enterprise cloud subscription revenues are forecast to reach $67B by 2018, attaining a CAGR of 17.3% in the forecast period.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By 2018, 59% of the total cloud workloads will be Software-as-a-Service (SaaS) workloads, up from 41% in 2013&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/Forecast-SAAS.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;SaaS Forecast&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;$78.43B in SaaS revenue will be generated in 2015, increasing to $132.57 in 2020, attaining a compound annual growth rate (CAGR) of 9.14%&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/Forecast-SAASRevenue.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;SaaS Revenue Forecast&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;42% of IT decision makers are planning to increase spending on cloud computing in 2015.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/Cloud-Computing-Spend.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Spend of Cloud Computing&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spending on cloud computing infrastructure and platforms is expected to grow at a 30% CAGR from 2013 through 2018 compared with 5% growth for the overall enterprise IT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/IAAS-PAAS.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Growth of IaaS &amp;amp; PaaS&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security (36%), cloud computing (31%) and mobile devices (28%) are the top 3 initiatives IT executives are planning to have their organizations focus on over the next 12 months&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/SMAC.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;SMAC Growth Initiatives&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By 2016 over 80% of enterprises globally will use IaaS, with investments in private cloud computing showing the greater growth.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/IAAS.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;IaaS adoption rate is high&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The SaaS Supply Chain Management (SCM) market is predicted to a $4.4B market by 2018, attaining a 19% CAGR from 2014 to 2018&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/SAAS-SCM.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;SaaS SCM&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Computing Market Overview</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Computing-Market-Overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Computing-Market-Overview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cloud Market Overview&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cloud marketplace is real; the cloud marketplace is now; and CSPs are well positioned to take advantage of this opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enterprises are steadily shifting their IT spending to cloud services.
While many are starting with hosted email and Web-based CRM applications, the adoption of Infrastructure-as-a-Service (IaaS) and Platforms-as-a-Service (PaaS) is increasing significantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly, service providers able to offer cloud services that meet and satisfy the insatiable enterprise demand for cloud computing will reap sustained and predictable revenue and profitability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cloud Computing Market Size (2013)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Overall Spending in Cloud Market    $131Bn&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall Cloud Services Market       $30Bn&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SaaS                                    $20-22 Bn&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IaaS                                    $6  Bn&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PaaS                                    $.5 Bn&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Others/Misc                             $3 Bn&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Need of Becoming CSP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extra Source of Revenue&lt;/strong&gt;
Service Providers are finding revenues from their traditional services shrinking due to excessive competition.
Value Added Services on top of their core services have provided them with the required extra revenue for many years but that is also leveling off.
Cloud Computing offers itself as the candidate for the next wave of value added services providing support to their revenue and the bottom line.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Increasing Loyalty and Reducing Churn&lt;/strong&gt;
Cloud Computing offers multiple reasons for the existing customers to stay longer because once they start using some cloud based services from one service provider, their stickiness and barrier to move away both increase significantly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When previously it was just a matter of signing up with the new service provider, with cloud computing in the portfolio, they have an added ‘migration cost’ of their data involved in order to move away and a potential downtime of critical services during switchover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Differentiation of Services&lt;/strong&gt;
With many providers in the same market segment, cloud computing provides a way for service providers to differentiate their services from the competition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Market Leadership&lt;/strong&gt;
Service Providers offering cloud computing are seen as driving the market and providing leadership. With hundreds of services coming in the cloud computing space, the trend is going to continue for many years to come.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Low Capex&lt;/strong&gt;
Offering Cloud Computing services is a low capex venture. With all larger software vendors offering service provider license agreements, the nature of business is basically pay as you grow with little CAPEX and OPEX directly related to revenue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monetization of Access Network&lt;/strong&gt;
Access Network is very expensive and more so for wireless service providers because of increasing spectrum license costs among others. Cloud Computing offers an added range of high value services to be offered over the same access infrastructure, offering better avenues of monetization of the same network.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extension of Technology&lt;/strong&gt;
All Service Providers are technology driven industries and already have expertise in managing their core networks and running their operations uninterrupted and also have monitoring systems in place for their core services. Adding cloud computing to their offerings does not add any significant requirements for them in terms of expertise or equipment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Higher Margins&lt;/strong&gt;
Cloud Computing comes with multiple avenues in adding value. They could be in providing managed services, monitoring of services, maintenance and upgrades of services, different levels of support and so on. Such personalized services allow higher margins than base services which are now increasingly commoditized.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Factors Favouring and Challenging Cloud Adoption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/Cloud-Adoption.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Cloud Adoptions Pros and Cons&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Stack Swift</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/OpenStackSwift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/OpenStackSwift/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ELIMINATE VENDOR LOCK-IN&lt;/strong&gt; OpenStack Swift is open source.
Change providers without changing your application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LOW COST&lt;/strong&gt; Choice of industry standard hardware that is available from multiple vendors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Features&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deployment Automation- Deployment of availability zones based on hardware.
Centralized Management- Provides diagnostics, monitoring data, alerts to controller.
Capacity Management- Orchestrates capacity additions and removals without interruption.
Monitoring- Monitors 500+ data points per node and integration with ganglia and nagios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hardware Overview:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proxy Tier- Proxy nodes handles all incoming API requests. Once a proxy server receives a request, it will determine which storage node to connect to, based on the URL of the object. A minimum of two nodes should be deployed in the proxy tier for redundancy. The proxy tier also includes ssl-terminators and authentication services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Storage Tier- When a client uploads data to SwiftStack, the proxy tier will write data in three different availability zones in the storage tier. For incoming read requests, one of the three replicas of the data will be served. Subsequently, each storage node and drive that is added to a Swift cluster will not only provide additional storage capacity, but will also increase the aggregate IO capacity of the cluster as there are more drives available to serve incoming read requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Networking- A typical SwiftStack deployment will have a front-facing ‘access’ network (to run the proxy and authentication services) and a back-end ‘storage’ network.  As there are three copies of each object, an incoming write is sent to three storage nodes. Therefore network capacity for writes needs to be considered in proportion to overall workload.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommended System Requirement:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proxy Tier- Typically, Proxy servers are 1U systems with a minimum of 12 GB RAM. For small SwiftStack clusters, the storage services and proxy services can run on the same physical nodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Storage Tier- Storage nodes are typically higher ­density 2U, 3U or 4U nodes with 12-­‐36 SATA disks each. A good rule of thumb is approximately 1 GB of RAM for each TB of Disk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drives- 2TB or 3TB 7200 RPM SATA drives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Networking- Storage nodes can be provisioned with 1GbE (single gigabit) or 10GbE network interface depending on expected workload and desired performance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding PaaS</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/PAAS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/PAAS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Platform as a Service (PaaS) is a way to rent hardware, operating systems, storage and network capacity over the Internet. The service delivery model allows the customer to rent virtualized servers and associated services for running existing applications or developing and testing new ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PaaS provides complete stack of development tools which are accessed by developers via web browser to create enterprise level applications, without installing anything besides a web browser on their computers, and deploying these over the complex &amp;amp; heterogeneous infrastructure without any specific skills required. PaaS offerings facilitate the deployment of applications without the cost and complexity of buying and managing the underlying hardware and software and provisioning hosting capabilities, providing all of the facilities required to support the complete life cycle of building and delivering web applications and services entirely available from the Internet. PaaS offerings may include facilities for application design, application development, testing, deployment and hosting as well as application services such as team collaboration, web service integration and marshaling, database integration, security, scalability, storage, persistence, state management, application versioning, application instrumentation and developer community facilitation. These services may be provisioned as an integrated solution over the web.
At a high-level, a PaaS helps organizations, specifically developers, realize the benefits of cloud computing by providing a fast and scalable way to host applications in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technically, a PaaS is an Application Platform comprised of an operating system, middleware and other software that allows applications to run on the cloud with much of the management, security, scaling and other stack related headaches abstracted away. This allows you to focus on two things: customers and developing your application. Let the PaaS deal with system administration details like setting up servers or VMs, installing libraries or frameworks, configuring testing tools, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Traditional Model:&lt;/strong&gt;
Building and running on-premise applications has always been complex, expensive, and risky. Each application required hardware, an operating system, a database, middleware, Web servers, and other software. Once the stack was assembled, a team of developers had to navigate complex programming models like J2EE and .NET. A team of network, database, and system management experts was needed to keep everything up and running. Inevitably, a business requirement would require a change to the application, which would then kick off a lengthy development, test, and redeployment cycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Large companies often needed specialized facilities to house their data centers. Enormous amounts of electricity also were needed to power the servers as well as the systems to keep them cool. Finally, a failover site was needed to mirror the data center so information could be replicated in case of a disaster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The New Model:&lt;/strong&gt;
PaaS provides the entire infrastructure needed to run applications over the Internet. It is delivered in the same way as a utility like electricity or water. Users simply “tap in” and take what they need without worrying about the complexity behind the scenes. And like a utility, PaaS is based on a metering or subscription model so users only pay for what they use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With PaaS, ISVs and corporate IT departments can focus on innovation instead of complex infrastructure. By leveraging the PaaS, organizations can redirect a significant portion of their budgets from “keeping the lights on” to creating applications that provide real business value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This model is driving a new era of mass innovation. For the first time, developers around the world can access unlimited computing power. Now, anyone with an Internet connection can build powerful applications and easily deploy them to users wherever they’re located&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefits Of Cloud Computing</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Computing-Benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Computing-Benefits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accelerates your business by providing limitless scalability and transforming ideas with a greater speed into marketable services and products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brings powerful IT resources to the world. Organizations across the globe can access information technologies which were earlier out of reach, computing infrastructure and world class applications are available without considerable investment up front.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unlocks revenue potential and makes new business models available for any business.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Companies can now collaborate more efficiently to drive business value and innovations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud reduces operating risks as well as improves information management. Protects sensitive information and simplifies disaster recovery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud transforms the economics of the industry from capital driven to pay-as you go. Costs are metered according to the requirements and usage. SLA guarantees the capabilities when you need them. There is greater utilization of the underlying infrastructure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The core advantage of cloud computing is its ability to access high performance computing systems on the basis of sharing and time model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use of standard technology is encouraged and facilitated while delivering the latest technology and with full optimization of resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Things To Look For In Your Cloud Service Provider</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Service-Provider/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Service-Provider/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The cloud computing market is exploding with a large number of new entrants. If you are shopping around for a cloud service provider (CSP), here are ten things you should keep in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Expertise&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A cloud computing service is not a commodity: it is not as simple as providing you with a computer in a server farm. It requires a lot of technical expertise to set up the right system that guarantees security for your data and lets you run your business without interruption. Thus, the first thing you have to look in your CSP is the quality of their team and their technical prowess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trust&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are going to migrate your sensitive enterprise data to a third-party server. You really need to be able to trust that organization. Interview their team and see if they are the people with whom you can trust your confidential corporate information. Ask for references and testimonials. Research the vendor thoroughly before trusting them with your data. Also, look for their industry memberships and accreditations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uptime guarantees&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can you afford to have your server down for hours in the middle of the week? If not, ask for uptime guarantees from CSPs. Ask their existing customers about previous outages, and how soon the vendor had the services restored. Anything more than 1 hour’s downtime/month is unacceptable for most businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools available&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does the CSP have a good tool set to help you with analytics, data management, security, etc? A good tool set provided by the CSP can help you cut the costs of your IT operations team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ease of migration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will it be easy to migrate your data and applications to the cloud? Migration is one of the biggest pain-points for enterprises moving to the cloud, so check if your CSP provides tools and support to make this process less painful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance guarantees&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as uptimes are important, so are performance metrics. Ask the CSP about the servers they are using, the disc access speeds, the processor types, network bandwidth and availability of SSDs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customer Support&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are going to trust your corporate IT infrastructure with a third party. What if your server crashes at the start of the day due to a malfunctioning app? Are you sure you can get it fixed ASAP? Customer support is critical, and it is important that the vendor provides you 24-hour technical support, at least on weekdays. If the support is poor, you can expect to spend a lot of money on your in-house IT team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How serious are they about Security?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security should be a top priority for your CSP. Ask about the steps they take to ensure the security of your data and applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Third-party compliance audits&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have the CSP had their service audited by third-party compliance teams to back up their claims? The industry body, the International Association of Managed Service Providers (MSP Alliance), has a certification standard (UCS) that is used to certify CSPs. Check if your CSP is accredited by it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, it is all about the cost. Check for all the fees (one-time fees, monthly fees, usage fees, etc.) and make sure they are clearly spelled out in the contract.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Case Study Precise</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Case-Study-Precise/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Case-Study-Precise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Precise(a developer of application performance management systems), was spun out of its parent company Symantec and into a private company. Suddenly, we had 1,000 customers to support, and a limited IT department. Symantec offered to sell us licenses for SAP and other enterprise software packages that we had been using. But in our new structure, we needed applications that were scaled down and easier to support. We ditched the world of licensed software and annual commitments to large capital expenses on equipment — the traditional way of doing IT — in favor of cloud, SaaS and virtualization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a midsize company with more than 200 employees, it was a tectonic shift. But after a year-long migration of our IT infrastructure and applications to the cloud, we shaved more than $2 million, or 70 percent, from our annual IT budget. Here’s how we did it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first priority was to find a solution to support our customers, so we chose Salesforce and NetSuite for the front and back-office solutions. It took a single data analyst a mere five hours to migrate all of our data from SAP to the new systems. For customer support, we chose Drupal and for marketing we chose Marketo — both of which were seamlessly integrated using WebSphere Cast Iron Cloud Integration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up, we had to deal with the Microsoft Exchange servers that we’d inherited from Symantec. Microsoft Exchange can be a bear to support with a slim staff, so we opted forGoogle Mail instead. The e-mail migration took about five days, and later we also moved from Microsoft  SharePoint  Sites for collaboration. The cool thing is, employees don’t have to do everything on Google. They can still access their favorite Microsoft Office applications, such as Excel, or use Outlook front-end if they wish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also went through a major server virtualization project in engineering — chopping off about 60 percent of our server expenses — and switched to AT&amp;amp;T fiber for networking and adopted VoIP for telephony.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of the technologies that I’ve mentioned are new or even groundbreaking. But the fact that we could adopt all of them in a short period of time, integrate them using a single data analyst and realize such financial benefits is astounding. Even five years ago, small and midsize companies couldn’t afford state-of-the-art technologies to run their businesses. That’s all changed — and the playing field for IT sophistication has leveled out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only is using newer, Web technologies more affordable, but they’re also more reliable. That’s been the case at Precise, at least. We haven’t had any issues from moving to a SaaS environment. We didn’t spend a bunch of money on hordes of consultants to get everything in place. It really was that simple. I give credit to our former IT director, Sharon Cohen, for choosing the right strategy and the right partners — that’s key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our transition to the cloud means that today we spend less time managing all the plumbing and more time working on our own products. We’re even looking at deploying cloud-based systems for R &amp;amp; D. And let’s not forget, we are saving more than $2 million per year. That’s the kind of money companies of our size, which comprise the bulk of the U.S. economy, can really put to good use. We can use those savings to hire strategic new employees or bring new features and services to our customers. For midsize companies, there’s no doubt:  rip out your on-premise software apps, go SaaS and adopt the cloud across the board.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shifting of Guard from providers to consumers in Cloud</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Shifting-of-Guard-from-providers-to-consumers-in-Cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Shifting-of-Guard-from-providers-to-consumers-in-Cloud/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;For a long time, the power in the IT industry has been in the hands of the providers. This is due to three industry characteristics that, while still present, are beginning to change. The first is the pricing and investment model. In a traditional hardware/software model, the deployment of any IT system has potentially large initial investment costs: the cost of purchasing necessary hardware and software licenses, project development costs, and so on. This &lt;strong&gt;large initial investment contributes to vendor lock-in,&lt;/strong&gt; since customers are usually unwilling to make these expenses a second time in order to change providers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;lack of interoperability&lt;/strong&gt; between systems is the second. The harder it is to move your stuff from one system to another, the less likely it is that you will even be willing to try the new system. Even worse, this resistance to change tends to increase over time, since people will have more and more data stored, and will be used to the way the current systems work. This does not mean that new systems are necessarily better, but if users are unwilling to try them out, they’ll never know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the &lt;strong&gt;lack of transparency regarding pricing models and structure&lt;/strong&gt; is the third source of power. It allowed providers to come up with complex pricing structures that make any sort of price comparison nearly impossible. In order to compare prices, customers are forced to get in touch with salespeople and request proposals, going through a lengthy process. And the high initial investment makes any “try it out first” movement much harder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-consumer-friendly-cloud&#34;&gt;A consumer-friendly cloud&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately for IT consumers, the shift to services, and especially cloud-based services, has been steadily shifting this power back into the hands of consumers. First, cloud computing has a great potential to democratize IT solutions by eliminating the entry barriers into this market. It can eliminate entry barriers for consumers by &lt;strong&gt;removing the need for upfront investment.&lt;/strong&gt; It is much easier for a small start-up to have dozens or even hundreds of server instances running at a given time, without the need to buy these servers, build a data center, or anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cloud also reduces barriers for providers. Being on the web allows any new provider to easily reach a much broader audience without the need for large marketing investments. It also simplifies distribution, since cloud-based software usually runs on the browser, with no need for installation procedures. This, in turn, simplifies support, since the problem of variability in client machine configuration is reduced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having more providers means having more competition, and this also means more power to consumers. The more competition there is, the more pressure is made towards lower prices, improved and diversified offerings, and better service. We are already seeing &lt;strong&gt;benefits of competition in the cloud space:&lt;/strong&gt; the only reason Rackspace dropped its inbound data-transfer fees was because all its competitors were doing it – and advertising that Rackspace didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is another important point in cloud-based services. Providers of all sorts, from infrastructure to software, are adopting &lt;strong&gt;simpler pricing models&lt;/strong&gt; to better engage customers. Unlike what we saw before, providers are fully advertising their prices, making it easier for consumers to compare different offerings. This price and feature transparency is second nature to cloud companies, because it is part of what we have come to expect from the web. I should be able to compare prices of cloud services in the same way that I can compare the price of physical products across several web retailers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we are seeing much &lt;strong&gt;improved interoperability between services.&lt;/strong&gt; This is especially true for cloud-based software offerings. While lack of interoperability was interesting for in-house software vendors because it created vendor lock-in, users already come to the cloud with the expectation of being able to easily export the data. The very nature of the way that software is sold in the cloud, on a pay-as-you-go model, strengthens the idea that if the user may cancel his contract at any time, he should be able to export his data from my service at any given time. Yes, there are still limitations and format inconsistencies, but many competing cloud-based software providers already offer automated import/export of data from their competitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same thing, to a certain extent, happens with infrastructure providers. In theory, if my application is properly designed to run on cloud instances, it should make no great difference to me if it is running on an Amazon, Rackspace, or anyone else’s cloud server. In fact, I should be able to run on whichever instance is the cheapest one at that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cloud model, then, is much more consumer-friendly than any in-house model, either for software or for servers. The logic is similar to what happens in any other service: if I need to go to a dentist when I’m a child, I don’t have to purchase a dentist’s chair and instruments, and my dental records are not kept in a format that only that dentist will understand. If I want to change dentists in the future, all I have to do is take my records with me and visit another one. The same goes for the cloud: there is no upfront investment, and the information is more accessible, so any future migration is much easier.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future Of Computing</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Future-Of-Computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Future-Of-Computing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new service for students and consumers aims to bring a complete Windows experience on whatever device you own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The future of computing may not lie in faster processors and larger hard drives. Pretty soon, your computer itself could move to the cloud — easy, affordable, accessible from anywhere and most importantly, from almost any device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could stop worrying about what kind of laptop to buy, how to maintain it or worry about how soon it’ll be obsolete. You could carry one device (maybe your existing smartphone) and use it as your go-to device for work, play &amp;amp; travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HOW IT WORKS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nivio can give you the full power (and flexibility) of a Windows 7 environment on just about any PC hardware or even a MAC — all within a web browser — thanks to desktop virtualisation. Your virtual desktop is placed on their servers and you can access it from anywhere, on any machine — the hardware doesn’t matter. You’ll get the same experience on MAC, PC or Linux as long as you have a stable broadband connection (3G, DSL or equivalent).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WHAT IT MEANS FOR THE PC INDUSTRY&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This kind of innovation could be disruptive for the PC industry as a whole. Think about it — currently PC manufacturers are in a tizzy, trying to convince you that their machine is the best, the fastest and the most reliable. But the truth is, in an online world, the amount of gigahertz and gigabytes you have simply doesn’t matter! All the processing and all the number crunching will be done on remote servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ACCESS FROM MOBILE DEVICES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nivio can also offer the full Windows operating system experience on your Android or iOS device. Since Nivio’s service relies on the cloud and not on hardware, you can get the same experience (using a free app) on a portable device. You can also use it on a 2G/EDGE network in an emergency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AN INTERESTING USE CASE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The idea is that you could just take your phone, attach a larger screen and a Bluetooth keyboard and it’ll become your desktop” explains Sachin Duggal, co-founder and ‘chief wizard’ of the UK and India-based enterprise.
Nivio promises to ‘complete’ your existing device; give it a second life. They want to offer the full functionality of a PC on any device, so that you carry less devices, not multiple devices with each one suited to a different task. Their mission is to make affordable software and content available to anyone, on their fa-MAC vourite devices OS X , anywhere LION in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KEY ADVANTAGES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The advantages of using Nivio are tremendous. We’ve already mentioned that it’s hardware independent. But the other main advantages are affordability, security, freedom from software piracy, and accessibility. In an essence, you’re renting all the software — Windows and whatever other programs you need — instead of buying them outright at high prices. All your files can be online — they offer 10GB of online storage for free with more available for a small fee. “Because the experience is purely utility based — it’s on/off in an instant. You don’t have to install software either; just select it and it’s available” says Sachin. “We’re fairly into the notion of bringing magic back to computing — because the user is subtracted from having to understand how it all works — it just works! This is very similar to other items that a consumer may use – a car, a TV or mobile phone. In a PC, a consumer traditionally has to understand a lot more about how it works, but we want to change that” he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WHAT’S NEXT?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since hardware requirements are minimal, you could have a complete operating system experience on just about any internet connected device, such as a TV, set top box, car A/V system or even a refrigerator! As of last evening, Nivio went live in the United States and will be available for Indian consumers by the end of March this year. To find out more, visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://in.nivio.com&#34;&gt;http://in.nivio.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Quick Hands on Since your desktop resides on the cloud, the experience of using Nivio’s nDesktop is pretty similar, whether you access it from an iPhone, iPad or computer. When you login, you see the familiar Windows desktop. A session stays active for 3 hours after you disconnect — which means that if the power goes out, you can reconnect later within 3 hours and everything will be as you left it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using it on Mobile Devices On Android and iOS devices, you need an app called Pocket Cloud Pro that connects you to your Nivio nDesktop. Once connected, you’ll get the complete Windows 7 experience, complete with on-screen keyboard and right-click. You can also get the nDrive app that gives you access to your online storage. While the apps will be available on the respective US app stores from today, Indian consumers will get access to the apps (and the corresponding service) only by mid to end March 2012.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Similar Services&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nivio is not the only one to offer cloud computing services. Citrix Systems, a US-based company offers the XenDesktop (a desktop virtualisation service, similar to Nivio’s) for enterprise customers. A similar offering by OnLive offers high resolution video gaming on hardware that was not originally supported. For instance, you could play a full PC game on a MAC or portable Android device. OnLive also offers a basic set top box that connects to your TV with accompanying gaming controller. This device effectively turns your computer into a gaming console. Since all the processing is done at the back end, the end user device just needs a fast internet connection and the ability to play HD video.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Data Security in Cloud Computing - Abstract</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Enhancing-Data-Security-Abstract/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Enhancing-Data-Security-Abstract/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cloud Computing is a new mechanism to deliver products from producer to consumer in a very different and efficient style of computing. It has revolutionized not only the IT industry but has also revolutionized the hardware and software industry. It is growing leaps and bounds and has only bright sky ahead. But will you love to see a bright sky with embraces of black holes? Obviously you won’t, similarly security is the main issue which acts as a blackhole to the whole system of it specialists in this domain. The main mission of security is to limit access to the authorized person, who can see, modify only that data which they are associated with. When we talk about the security of data in Cloud Computing the vendor has to ensure assurance to convince the customer on the security issues. Organizations are using cloud computing for confidential issues for their business applications though guaranteeing the security is difficult. This paper is divided into different sections such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Introduction to Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Benefits of Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Challenges of Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enhancement of Security.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This paper will enlighten the various improved methods for dealing with data security in the domain of authentication, encryption, decryption, biometrics, cryptography and public key infrastructure in the venture of Cloud Computing. We will focus on the security enhancement of cryptography and biometrics by their combinations. This paper is aimed at being a reference point to understand the basic security ideas for the newcomers and intended to promote more activities and research in these critical and very important security issues which has to be addressed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Efficiency - Theory of Einstein</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Einstein/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Einstein/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/Cloud-Einstein.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Cloud Einstein Theory&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Benefit To God</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Humor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Humor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/Cloud-Humor.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Cloud Humor&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Homework</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Homework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Homework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/Cloud-Homework.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Cloud Homework&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
