<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Virtualization on Blog </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/tags/virtualization/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
    
    <updated>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefits of Storage Virtualization</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Benefits-Storage-Virtualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Benefits-Storage-Virtualization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved Storage Management in an IT environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better availability and estimation of downtime required with automated management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to migrate data while retaining  I/O access (Non disruptive data migration).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce the number of SAN devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decrease in Power consumed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time Saving.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ease in Data Replication.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy backup, archiving and recovery tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expansion of Storage Capacity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy Updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to increase Storage Volume Size in real time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increased loading and backup speed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Storage Virtualization</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/What-is-Storage-Virtualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/What-is-Storage-Virtualization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is the abstraction of physical media (hard disks or solid state drives etc) from the attaching servers which treats the storage as a single logical entity without regard to the hierarchy of physical media that is involved. Storage virtualization means adding an abstraction layer of software that hides the physical devices from the user and allows all devices to be managed as a single pool.
It adds a new layer of software or hardware in between the storage systems and servers so that the applications would not require to know to which logical drive, partitions or storage subsystems the data resides in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within the context of a storage system, there are two primary types of virtualization that can occur:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Block virtualization&lt;/strong&gt; used in this context refers to the abstraction (separation) of logical storage (partition) from physical storage so that it may be accessed without regard to physical storage or heterogeneous structure. This separation allows the administrators of the storage system greater flexibility in how they manage storage for end users. The act of applying virtualization , to one or more block based (storage) services for the purpose of providing a new aggregated, higher level, richer, simpler, secure, etc., block service to clients. Block virtualization functions can be nested. A disk drive, RAID system or volume manager all perform some form of block address to (different) block address mapping or aggregation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;File virtualization&lt;/strong&gt; addresses the NAS challenges by eliminating the dependencies between the data accessed at the file level and the location where the files are physically stored. This provides opportunities to optimize storage use and server consolidation and to perform non-disruptive file migrations. File virtualization is the creation of an abstraction layer between file servers and the clients that access those file servers. Once deployed, the file virtualization layer manages files and file systems across servers, allowing administrators to present clients with one logical file mount for all servers&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization &amp; Private Cloud</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Virtualization-Private-Cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Virtualization-Private-Cloud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Virtualization of computers or operating systems hides the physical characteristics of a computing platform from users; instead it shows another abstract computing platform. A hypervisor is a piece of virtualization software that allows multiple operating systems to run on a host computer concurrently. Virtualization providers include VMware, Microsoft, and Citrix Systems. Virtualization is an enabler of cloud computing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently some vendors have described solutions that emulate cloud computing on private networks, referring to these as “private” or “internal” clouds (where “public” or “external” cloud describes cloud computing in the traditional mainstream sense). Private cloud products claim to deliver some of the benefits of cloud computing without the pitfalls. Hybrid solutions are also possible: building internal clouds and connecting customer data centers to those of external cloud providers. It has been reported that Eli Lilly wants to benefit from both internal and external clouds3 and that Amylin6 is looking at private cloud VMware as a complement to EC2. Other experts, however, are skeptical: one has even gone as far as to describe private clouds as absolute rubbish.7&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Platform Computing has recently launched a cloud management system, Platform ISF, enabling customers to manage workload across both virtual and physical environments and support multiple hypervisors and operating systems from a single interface. VMware, the market leader in virtualization technology, is moving into cloud technologies in a big way, with vSphere 4. The company is building a huge partner network of service providers and is also releasing a “vCloud API”. VMware wants customers to build a series of “virtual data centers”, each tailored to meet different requirements, and then have the ability to move workloads in the virtual data centers to the infrastructure provided by cloud vendors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cisco, EMC and VMware have formed a new venture called Acadia. Its strategy for private cloud computing is based on Cisco’s servers and networking, VMware’s server virtualization and EMC’s storage. (Note, by the way, that EMC owns nearly 85% of VMware.) Other vendors, such as Google, disagree with VMware’s emphasis on private clouds; in return VMware says Google’s online applications are not ready for the enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
