<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Posts on Blog </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
    
    <updated>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Case Study Precise</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Case-Study-Precise/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Case-Study-Precise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Precise(a developer of application performance management systems), was spun out of its parent company Symantec and into a private company. Suddenly, we had 1,000 customers to support, and a limited IT department. Symantec offered to sell us licenses for SAP and other enterprise software packages that we had been using. But in our new structure, we needed applications that were scaled down and easier to support. We ditched the world of licensed software and annual commitments to large capital expenses on equipment — the traditional way of doing IT — in favor of cloud, SaaS and virtualization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a midsize company with more than 200 employees, it was a tectonic shift. But after a year-long migration of our IT infrastructure and applications to the cloud, we shaved more than $2 million, or 70 percent, from our annual IT budget. Here’s how we did it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first priority was to find a solution to support our customers, so we chose Salesforce and NetSuite for the front and back-office solutions. It took a single data analyst a mere five hours to migrate all of our data from SAP to the new systems. For customer support, we chose Drupal and for marketing we chose Marketo — both of which were seamlessly integrated using WebSphere Cast Iron Cloud Integration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up, we had to deal with the Microsoft Exchange servers that we’d inherited from Symantec. Microsoft Exchange can be a bear to support with a slim staff, so we opted forGoogle Mail instead. The e-mail migration took about five days, and later we also moved from Microsoft  SharePoint  Sites for collaboration. The cool thing is, employees don’t have to do everything on Google. They can still access their favorite Microsoft Office applications, such as Excel, or use Outlook front-end if they wish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also went through a major server virtualization project in engineering — chopping off about 60 percent of our server expenses — and switched to AT&amp;amp;T fiber for networking and adopted VoIP for telephony.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of the technologies that I’ve mentioned are new or even groundbreaking. But the fact that we could adopt all of them in a short period of time, integrate them using a single data analyst and realize such financial benefits is astounding. Even five years ago, small and midsize companies couldn’t afford state-of-the-art technologies to run their businesses. That’s all changed — and the playing field for IT sophistication has leveled out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only is using newer, Web technologies more affordable, but they’re also more reliable. That’s been the case at Precise, at least. We haven’t had any issues from moving to a SaaS environment. We didn’t spend a bunch of money on hordes of consultants to get everything in place. It really was that simple. I give credit to our former IT director, Sharon Cohen, for choosing the right strategy and the right partners — that’s key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our transition to the cloud means that today we spend less time managing all the plumbing and more time working on our own products. We’re even looking at deploying cloud-based systems for R &amp;amp; D. And let’s not forget, we are saving more than $2 million per year. That’s the kind of money companies of our size, which comprise the bulk of the U.S. economy, can really put to good use. We can use those savings to hire strategic new employees or bring new features and services to our customers. For midsize companies, there’s no doubt:  rip out your on-premise software apps, go SaaS and adopt the cloud across the board.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shifting of Guard from providers to consumers in Cloud</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Shifting-of-Guard-from-providers-to-consumers-in-Cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Shifting-of-Guard-from-providers-to-consumers-in-Cloud/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;For a long time, the power in the IT industry has been in the hands of the providers. This is due to three industry characteristics that, while still present, are beginning to change. The first is the pricing and investment model. In a traditional hardware/software model, the deployment of any IT system has potentially large initial investment costs: the cost of purchasing necessary hardware and software licenses, project development costs, and so on. This &lt;strong&gt;large initial investment contributes to vendor lock-in,&lt;/strong&gt; since customers are usually unwilling to make these expenses a second time in order to change providers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;lack of interoperability&lt;/strong&gt; between systems is the second. The harder it is to move your stuff from one system to another, the less likely it is that you will even be willing to try the new system. Even worse, this resistance to change tends to increase over time, since people will have more and more data stored, and will be used to the way the current systems work. This does not mean that new systems are necessarily better, but if users are unwilling to try them out, they’ll never know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the &lt;strong&gt;lack of transparency regarding pricing models and structure&lt;/strong&gt; is the third source of power. It allowed providers to come up with complex pricing structures that make any sort of price comparison nearly impossible. In order to compare prices, customers are forced to get in touch with salespeople and request proposals, going through a lengthy process. And the high initial investment makes any “try it out first” movement much harder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-consumer-friendly-cloud:1e26d8b33ceeb9d99961bbb5f007f8db&#34;&gt;A consumer-friendly cloud&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately for IT consumers, the shift to services, and especially cloud-based services, has been steadily shifting this power back into the hands of consumers. First, cloud computing has a great potential to democratize IT solutions by eliminating the entry barriers into this market. It can eliminate entry barriers for consumers by &lt;strong&gt;removing the need for upfront investment.&lt;/strong&gt; It is much easier for a small start-up to have dozens or even hundreds of server instances running at a given time, without the need to buy these servers, build a data center, or anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cloud also reduces barriers for providers. Being on the web allows any new provider to easily reach a much broader audience without the need for large marketing investments. It also simplifies distribution, since cloud-based software usually runs on the browser, with no need for installation procedures. This, in turn, simplifies support, since the problem of variability in client machine configuration is reduced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having more providers means having more competition, and this also means more power to consumers. The more competition there is, the more pressure is made towards lower prices, improved and diversified offerings, and better service. We are already seeing &lt;strong&gt;benefits of competition in the cloud space:&lt;/strong&gt; the only reason Rackspace dropped its inbound data-transfer fees was because all its competitors were doing it – and advertising that Rackspace didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is another important point in cloud-based services. Providers of all sorts, from infrastructure to software, are adopting &lt;strong&gt;simpler pricing models&lt;/strong&gt; to better engage customers. Unlike what we saw before, providers are fully advertising their prices, making it easier for consumers to compare different offerings. This price and feature transparency is second nature to cloud companies, because it is part of what we have come to expect from the web. I should be able to compare prices of cloud services in the same way that I can compare the price of physical products across several web retailers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we are seeing much &lt;strong&gt;improved interoperability between services.&lt;/strong&gt; This is especially true for cloud-based software offerings. While lack of interoperability was interesting for in-house software vendors because it created vendor lock-in, users already come to the cloud with the expectation of being able to easily export the data. The very nature of the way that software is sold in the cloud, on a pay-as-you-go model, strengthens the idea that if the user may cancel his contract at any time, he should be able to export his data from my service at any given time. Yes, there are still limitations and format inconsistencies, but many competing cloud-based software providers already offer automated import/export of data from their competitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same thing, to a certain extent, happens with infrastructure providers. In theory, if my application is properly designed to run on cloud instances, it should make no great difference to me if it is running on an Amazon, Rackspace, or anyone else’s cloud server. In fact, I should be able to run on whichever instance is the cheapest one at that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cloud model, then, is much more consumer-friendly than any in-house model, either for software or for servers. The logic is similar to what happens in any other service: if I need to go to a dentist when I’m a child, I don’t have to purchase a dentist’s chair and instruments, and my dental records are not kept in a format that only that dentist will understand. If I want to change dentists in the future, all I have to do is take my records with me and visit another one. The same goes for the cloud: there is no upfront investment, and the information is more accessible, so any future migration is much easier.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future Of Computing</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Future-Of-Computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Future-Of-Computing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new service for students and consumers aims to bring a complete Windows experience on whatever device you own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The future of computing may not lie in faster processors and larger hard drives. Pretty soon, your computer itself could move to the cloud — easy, affordable, accessible from anywhere and most importantly, from almost any device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could stop worrying about what kind of laptop to buy, how to maintain it or worry about how soon it’ll be obsolete. You could carry one device (maybe your existing smartphone) and use it as your go-to device for work, play &amp;amp; travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HOW IT WORKS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nivio can give you the full power (and flexibility) of a Windows 7 environment on just about any PC hardware or even a MAC — all within a web browser — thanks to desktop virtualisation. Your virtual desktop is placed on their servers and you can access it from anywhere, on any machine — the hardware doesn’t matter. You’ll get the same experience on MAC, PC or Linux as long as you have a stable broadband connection (3G, DSL or equivalent).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WHAT IT MEANS FOR THE PC INDUSTRY&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This kind of innovation could be disruptive for the PC industry as a whole. Think about it — currently PC manufacturers are in a tizzy, trying to convince you that their machine is the best, the fastest and the most reliable. But the truth is, in an online world, the amount of gigahertz and gigabytes you have simply doesn’t matter! All the processing and all the number crunching will be done on remote servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ACCESS FROM MOBILE DEVICES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nivio can also offer the full Windows operating system experience on your Android or iOS device. Since Nivio’s service relies on the cloud and not on hardware, you can get the same experience (using a free app) on a portable device. You can also use it on a 2G/EDGE network in an emergency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AN INTERESTING USE CASE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The idea is that you could just take your phone, attach a larger screen and a Bluetooth keyboard and it’ll become your desktop” explains Sachin Duggal, co-founder and ‘chief wizard’ of the UK and India-based enterprise.
Nivio promises to ‘complete’ your existing device; give it a second life. They want to offer the full functionality of a PC on any device, so that you carry less devices, not multiple devices with each one suited to a different task. Their mission is to make affordable software and content available to anyone, on their fa-MAC vourite devices OS X , anywhere LION in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KEY ADVANTAGES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The advantages of using Nivio are tremendous. We’ve already mentioned that it’s hardware independent. But the other main advantages are affordability, security, freedom from software piracy, and accessibility. In an essence, you’re renting all the software — Windows and whatever other programs you need — instead of buying them outright at high prices. All your files can be online — they offer 10GB of online storage for free with more available for a small fee. “Because the experience is purely utility based — it’s on/off in an instant. You don’t have to install software either; just select it and it’s available” says Sachin. “We’re fairly into the notion of bringing magic back to computing — because the user is subtracted from having to understand how it all works — it just works! This is very similar to other items that a consumer may use – a car, a TV or mobile phone. In a PC, a consumer traditionally has to understand a lot more about how it works, but we want to change that” he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WHAT’S NEXT?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since hardware requirements are minimal, you could have a complete operating system experience on just about any internet connected device, such as a TV, set top box, car A/V system or even a refrigerator! As of last evening, Nivio went live in the United States and will be available for Indian consumers by the end of March this year. To find out more, visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://in.nivio.com&#34;&gt;http://in.nivio.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Quick Hands on Since your desktop resides on the cloud, the experience of using Nivio’s nDesktop is pretty similar, whether you access it from an iPhone, iPad or computer. When you login, you see the familiar Windows desktop. A session stays active for 3 hours after you disconnect — which means that if the power goes out, you can reconnect later within 3 hours and everything will be as you left it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using it on Mobile Devices On Android and iOS devices, you need an app called Pocket Cloud Pro that connects you to your Nivio nDesktop. Once connected, you’ll get the complete Windows 7 experience, complete with on-screen keyboard and right-click. You can also get the nDrive app that gives you access to your online storage. While the apps will be available on the respective US app stores from today, Indian consumers will get access to the apps (and the corresponding service) only by mid to end March 2012.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Similar Services&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nivio is not the only one to offer cloud computing services. Citrix Systems, a US-based company offers the XenDesktop (a desktop virtualisation service, similar to Nivio’s) for enterprise customers. A similar offering by OnLive offers high resolution video gaming on hardware that was not originally supported. For instance, you could play a full PC game on a MAC or portable Android device. OnLive also offers a basic set top box that connects to your TV with accompanying gaming controller. This device effectively turns your computer into a gaming console. Since all the processing is done at the back end, the end user device just needs a fast internet connection and the ability to play HD video.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Data Security in Cloud Computing - Abstract</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Enhancing-Data-Security-Abstract/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Enhancing-Data-Security-Abstract/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cloud Computing is a new mechanism to deliver products from producer to consumer in a very different and efficient style of computing. It has revolutionized not only the IT industry but has also revolutionized the hardware and software industry. It is growing leaps and bounds and has only bright sky ahead. But will you love to see a bright sky with embraces of black holes? Obviously you won’t, similarly security is the main issue which acts as a blackhole to the whole system of it specialists in this domain. The main mission of security is to limit access to the authorized person, who can see, modify only that data which they are associated with. When we talk about the security of data in Cloud Computing the vendor has to ensure assurance to convince the customer on the security issues. Organizations are using cloud computing for confidential issues for their business applications though guaranteeing the security is difficult. This paper is divided into different sections such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Introduction to Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Benefits of Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Challenges of Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enhancement of Security.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This paper will enlighten the various improved methods for dealing with data security in the domain of authentication, encryption, decryption, biometrics, cryptography and public key infrastructure in the venture of Cloud Computing. We will focus on the security enhancement of cryptography and biometrics by their combinations. This paper is aimed at being a reference point to understand the basic security ideas for the newcomers and intended to promote more activities and research in these critical and very important security issues which has to be addressed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Efficiency - Theory of Einstein</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Einstein/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Einstein/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/Cloud-Einstein.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Cloud Einstein Theory&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Benefit To God</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Humor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Humor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/Cloud-Humor.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Cloud Humor&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Homework</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Homework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Homework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/Cloud-Homework.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Cloud Homework&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Help Desk</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Help-Desk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Help-Desk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/Cloud-Help-Desk.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Cloud Help Desk&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Cloud Computing Architecture</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Basic-Cloud-Computing-Architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Basic-Cloud-Computing-Architecture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When talking about a cloud computing system, it’s helpful to divide it into two sections: the front endand the back end. They connect to each other through a network, usually the Internet. The front end is the side the computer user, or client, sees. The back end is the “cloud” section of the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The front end includes the client’s computer (or computer network) and the application required to access the cloud computing system.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt; Not all cloud computing systems have the same user interface. Services like Web-based e-mail programs leverage existing Web browsers like Internet Explorer or Firefox. Other systems have unique applications that provide network access to clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On the back end of the system are the various computers, servers and data storage systems that create the “cloud” of computing services.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt; In theory, a cloud computing system could include practically any computer program you can imagine, from data processing to video games. Usually, each application will have its own dedicated server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A central server administers the system, monitoring traffic and client demands to ensure everything runs smoothly.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt; It follows a set of rules called protocols and uses a special kind of software called middleware. Middleware allows networked computers to communicate with each other. Most of the time, servers don’t run at full capacity. That means there’s unused processing power going to waste. It’s possible to fool a physical server into thinking it’s actually multiple servers, each running with its own independent operating system. The technique is called server virtualization. By maximizing the output of individual servers, server virtualization reduces the need for more physical machines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a cloud computing company has a lot of clients, there’s likely to be a high demand for a lot of storage space. Some companies require hundreds of digital storage devices. Cloud computing systems need at least twice the number of storage devices it requires to keep all its clients’ information stored. That’s because these devices, like all computers, occasionally break down. A cloud computing system must make a copy of all its clients’ information and store it on other devices. The copies enable the central server to access backup machines to retrieve data that otherwise would be unreachable. Making copies of data as a backup is called redundancy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Cloud Computing will help?</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Importance-Cloud-Computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Importance-Cloud-Computing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The applications of cloud computing are practically limitless. With the right middleware, a cloud computing system could execute all the programs a normal computer could run. Potentially, everything from generic word processing software to customized computer programs designed for a specific company could work on a cloud computing system.
Why would anyone want to rely on another computer system to run programs and store data? Here are just a few reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clients would be able to access their applications and data from anywhere at any time. They could access the cloud computing system using any computer linked to the Internet. Data wouldn’t be confined to a hard drive on one user’s computer or even a corporation’s internal network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It could bring hardware costs down. Cloud computing systems would reduce the need for advanced hardware on the client side. You wouldn’t need to buy the fastest computer with the most memory, because the cloud system would take care of those needs for you. Instead, you could buy an inexpensive computer terminal. The terminal could include a monitor, input devices like a keyboard and mouse and just enough processing power to run the middleware necessary to connect to the cloud system. You wouldn’t need a large hard drive because you’d store all your information on a remote computer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corporations that rely on computers have to make sure they have the right software in place to achieve goals. Cloud computing systems give these organizations company-wide access to computer applications. The companies don’t have to buy a set of software or software licenses for every employee. Instead, the company could pay a metered fee to a cloud computing company.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Servers and digital storage devices take up space. Some companies rent physical space to store servers and databases because they don’t have it available on site. Cloud computing gives these companies the option of storing data on someone else’s hardware, removing the need for physical space on the front end.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corporations might save money on IT support. Streamlined hardware would, in theory, have fewer problems than a network of heterogeneous machines and operating systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the cloud computing system’s back end is a grid computing system, then the client could take advantage of the entire network’s processing power. Often, scientists and researchers work with calculations so complex that it would take years for individual computers to complete them. On a grid computing system, the client could send the calculation to the cloud for processing. The cloud system would tap into the processing power of all available computers on the back end, significantly speeding up the calculation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Data Specialist</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Data-Specialist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Data-Specialist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/Cloud-Specialist.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Are you sure this is how we get data into the Cloud?&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Enterprise Applications: 12 principles of operational readiness</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Enterprise-Operational-Readiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Enterprise-Operational-Readiness/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;enterprise-service-operational-principles:780d8bdc7e2b5b1e2903fcce2240231f&#34;&gt;Enterprise service operational principles&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These dozen statements describe how an enterprise service should be. If all these statements apply to my new enterprise service, I can happily stamp my operational approval on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have provided a few examples to make these statements a little clearer, but I have not described the actions required to get there. As you can imagine, putting these principles into practice for enterprise services is complicated. It’s almost impossible to get everything right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many cloud innovatorprovide services in one or two of these areas, to ease an organization’s workload. You can pay Green Hat to provide cloud-based performance testing tools, Core Cloud Inspect to check security, and Cloudkick to monitor infrastructure. A few big players like EMC and Novell have enough tools to take all the responsibility. The bigger your wallet, the more responsibility you can avoid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-enterprise-service:780d8bdc7e2b5b1e2903fcce2240231f&#34;&gt;My enterprise service:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Has been functionally tested&lt;/strong&gt;:- If a new business application has not yet been signed off by the guy paying the bills, I will waste my time carrying out operational tests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Has capacity&lt;/strong&gt;:- Sysadmins may want to scale up the disk space for a storage service and the bandwidth for a video chat service. They may scale down to a pocket calculator for a monitoring service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is resilient&lt;/strong&gt;:- This is the world of High Availability: double up on single points of failure, improve code quality, and even if something does fail, make sure the service handles it gracefully.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is recoverable&lt;/strong&gt;:- If the student deletes half the files or the computer room catches fire, service can be restored.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is reliable&lt;/strong&gt;:- Customers use Internet services 24 hours a day, but an intranet may only be needed during office hours. An intranet that is down every night may still be perfectly reliable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is scalable&lt;/strong&gt;:- What if the new service has traffic spikes or gets really popular? I may need to scale out by adding more servers. Wading through treacle is not attractive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is monitored&lt;/strong&gt;:- The operational support people must be alerted immediately if someone breaks into the computer room, if upstream services disappear, and if a process goes berserk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is supportable&lt;/strong&gt;:- If an architect designs an Internet bank that only runs on one server, how pleased will customers be when an operator turns off the bank to upgrade the memory?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is secure&lt;/strong&gt;:- Vulnerabilities get patched, an IDS (Intrusion Detection System) watches the network, and the security team have signed on the dotted line.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Has been pushed to the limit&lt;/strong&gt;:- The whole system has been thrashed, bottlenecks fixed and the system thrashed again and again. The service owner then knows how much performance can be squeezed out of her service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Has integrity&lt;/strong&gt;:- The customer support people won’t be plagued by calls from customers whose data is inconsistent, whose files have disappeared, or whose transactions were duplicated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Will operate within the SLA&lt;/strong&gt;:- The people sponsoring this service deserve to know how their investment is doing. The service builders automate the measurement and reports of the service level. Stakeholders can then help a failing service to succeed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization &amp; Private Cloud</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Virtualization-Private-Cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Virtualization-Private-Cloud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Virtualization of computers or operating systems hides the physical characteristics of a computing platform from users; instead it shows another abstract computing platform. A hypervisor is a piece of virtualization software that allows multiple operating systems to run on a host computer concurrently. Virtualization providers include VMware, Microsoft, and Citrix Systems. Virtualization is an enabler of cloud computing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently some vendors have described solutions that emulate cloud computing on private networks, referring to these as “private” or “internal” clouds (where “public” or “external” cloud describes cloud computing in the traditional mainstream sense). Private cloud products claim to deliver some of the benefits of cloud computing without the pitfalls. Hybrid solutions are also possible: building internal clouds and connecting customer data centers to those of external cloud providers. It has been reported that Eli Lilly wants to benefit from both internal and external clouds3 and that Amylin6 is looking at private cloud VMware as a complement to EC2. Other experts, however, are skeptical: one has even gone as far as to describe private clouds as absolute rubbish.7&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Platform Computing has recently launched a cloud management system, Platform ISF, enabling customers to manage workload across both virtual and physical environments and support multiple hypervisors and operating systems from a single interface. VMware, the market leader in virtualization technology, is moving into cloud technologies in a big way, with vSphere 4. The company is building a huge partner network of service providers and is also releasing a “vCloud API”. VMware wants customers to build a series of “virtual data centers”, each tailored to meet different requirements, and then have the ability to move workloads in the virtual data centers to the infrastructure provided by cloud vendors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cisco, EMC and VMware have formed a new venture called Acadia. Its strategy for private cloud computing is based on Cisco’s servers and networking, VMware’s server virtualization and EMC’s storage. (Note, by the way, that EMC owns nearly 85% of VMware.) Other vendors, such as Google, disagree with VMware’s emphasis on private clouds; in return VMware says Google’s online applications are not ready for the enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A $136-million storage idea: Hitesh Chellani and Anand Babu Periasamy launch cloud computing start-up</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Gluster-Startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Gluster-Startup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2005, when Hitesh Chellani and Anand Babu Periasamy decided to start their own cloud computing start-up, there weren’t too many believers to cheer them. The duo planned to build technology that would store everything that’s ever been filmed, taped, photographed, recorded, written or spoken – an idea so audacious that it was dismissed as a pipe dream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After several meetings at the local Starbucks in Fremont California, the two entrepreneurs launched Gluster with an angel investment of $200,000 from Silicon Valley entrepreneur and investor Anil Godhwani.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the money, few people believed that the two friends could turn this investment into a business that generates many millions of dollars in less than five years. Gluster was started inside Chellani’s home, with his daughter’s bedroom serving as the office and data centre occupied with noisy servers. So successful were they at chasing that dream that in just five years (2011), Red Hat, the world’s leading provider of open source solutions, acquired Gluster for approximately Rs 667 crore ($136 million) in an all-cash deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A lot of people told us what we were doing was impossible and we were crazy. But great ideas are always controversial in the beginning,” said AB Periasamy. The acquisition by Red Hat came through because the start-up had built an open-source storage platform for working with large amounts of data (terabytes, all the way up to petabytes and brontobytes) that ties together everything from the operating system layer to the file system and management interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We are offering this technology to our customers for the first time,” said Brian Stevens, CTO and vice-president, worldwide engineering, Red Hat. The story of Chellani and Periasamy might be common in the US. But in India, where the start-up set up its development centre, this was an uncommon tale of earlystage success. The two are firstgeneration entrepreneurs who did not come from a business family background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A computer engineer graduate from Annamalai University, Periasamy hails from Tharamangalam, a town in Salem district of Tamil Nadu. His father passed away when he was still in school. Faced with financial constraints, his mother had to mortgage the house to help him finish studies. Chellani, an electronics engineer, spent the first two decades of his life in Mumbai where his family of four lived in a 600 sqft apartment. His father had migrated from Pakistan during the partition and gone through a couple of unsuccessful businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beginning his career as a software engineer for Tata Unisys in India, Chellani worked for a while in Dubai to finance his way to a Master’s Degree in the US. Chellani met Periasamy there, while working together at California Digital and were part of the team that built the ‘Thunder’ supercomputer for Lawrence Livermore National Lab. When ‘Thunder’ was put into production in 2004, it was the second-fastest supercomputer in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once they joined forces to launch Gluster the duo battled disbelief until they landed their first customer order with Petroleos de Venezuela, the Venezuelan national oil company. Gluster soon expanded its services by selling opensource storage solutions to customers such as UK defence major BAE Systems, Stanford University, Deutsche Bank and the administrative office of the US courts. To become a significant storage player, Gluster needed serious funding. Just prior to securing first round of funding, the company had just $25,000 in the bank and it had to pay salary to 13 people. “But we did not lose hope” said Chellani.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Computing: What It Is and What It Can Do for You-Introduction</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Computing-Intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Computing-Intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cloud computing is one of the latest computer and business industry buzz words. It joins the ranks of virtualization, grid computing, and clustering, among others, in the IT industry. The problem is that, depending on your point of view, the definition of cloud computing can be quite different. Depending on your perspective, you could look at it from a business point of view or an application point of view, as well as others. This has created confusion on the definition and a fuzzy view as to what cloud computing is or even does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term cloud computing is overused and ill-defined, which has led many IT professionals and management to make assumptions as to what cloud computing does and how their companies can best utilize it. The IT Industry is not making it easier for their customers by offering many different definitions and products that only create confusion. This confusion is what the IT vendors are utilizing to create many different products and call them “cloud products.” Examples of this behavior can be seen by watching television ads that are being broadcast to everyone, not just IT professionals and management. One large IT company defines cloud computing in a way that only a person with a PhD. in linguistics and computer science could understand, but the ad tells you they are making a simple definition, and if you do not understand their definition then call up their professional services to “help” your company take advantage of cloud computing. This ad, as well as other marketing, makes the idea so complex that no one understands it, and this only makes cloud computing more of a “riddle wrapped in an enigma.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cloud is a great marketing term, with lots of hype behind it. This white paper will define cloud computing using a commonly accepted definition to get past the hype. Then we will discuss the different types of cloud computing, which also have added to the confusion as to what cloud computing is and does. We will end with ideas on how you can begin to implement the cloud in your environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term cloud, which is a familiar computer cliché that every computer networking professional has used as the “public internet” in a network design at one time or another, is a great place to start. The internet cloud is drawn into the network design as the part of the network that is not controlled by the company. It represents the unknown path to send data or information between the company and the customer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the IT professional, this is a well-understood concept and has been an acceptable practice for many years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, the internet cloud design has been shown to management over the years, and they also have a comfort level with the design and the concept. Now IT professionals do have a common knowledge of the internet cloud; however, if you combine cloud with computing, the definition becomes fuzzy, and there is no single acceptable meaning. If the concept comes up in a meeting, it begins to remind you of the story of the Emperor who has no clothes. No one wants to admit that they do not know exactly what cloud computing is, and this is why, many years ago, the industry developed Request For Comments (RFC). The RFCs were designed to standardize computer concepts. By standardizing, computers and the Internet were able to grow quickly, because companies had to abide by the RFC. This standardization made it easy for the producer and the consumer to avoid confusion on what was being produced and consumed. However, there are no RFCs for cloud computing, and this creates confusion as to what should or must be done to implement it. Without standardization, the producer and consumer are left to write their own rules and make their own definitions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
