<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Posts on Blog </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
    
    <updated>Sun, 15 May 2016 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>ScaleIOFeatures</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/ScaleIOFeatures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/ScaleIOFeatures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ScaleIO ECS is a software-only solution that uses application hosts’ local disks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Features:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simplified operation&lt;/strong&gt;- ECS enables IT administrator to manage the entire data center stack.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avoid capacity planning&lt;/strong&gt;- ECS is elastic, enabling you to add, move, remove servers and capacity during I/O operations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-healing&lt;/strong&gt;- It rebalances whenever capacity and/or servers are added.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dynamic performance allocation&lt;/strong&gt;- It provides dynamic allocation based on applications’ needs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Freedom of choice through hardware vendor lock-in elimination.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JedaNetwork</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/JedaNetwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/JedaNetwork/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jeda Networks game changing intelligent software product called the Fabric Network Controller (FNC) abstracts the complexity of a storage network into a software controller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Jeda FNC creates a high performance “storage network overlay” on top of an Ethernet fabric. This Software Defined Storage Network (SDSN) transforms the Ethernet fabric into a powerful and agile storage networking fabric. SDSNs solve the limitations of a fixed and rigid physical storage network—namely scalability, high cost, high complexity, and lack of agility&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Features:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maximize Performance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cut Management Costs-&lt;/strong&gt; mapping your SAN requirements to the physical Ethernet network&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No Hardware Lock-In&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The FNC has been successfully integrated with a number of multi-vendor 10Gb, 40Gb and 100 Gb Data Center Ethernet switches and as FNC is independent of the network hardware the FNC is software, it is network and access speed agnostic, so as speeds migrate to 100Gbs and beyond, the FNC will continue to work within these leaps of performance., it is 10, 40 and 100Gb Ethernet ready today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Stack Swift</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/OpenStackSwift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/OpenStackSwift/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ELIMINATE VENDOR LOCK-IN&lt;/strong&gt; OpenStack Swift is open source.
Change providers without changing your application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LOW COST&lt;/strong&gt; Choice of industry standard hardware that is available from multiple vendors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Features&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deployment Automation- Deployment of availability zones based on hardware.
Centralized Management- Provides diagnostics, monitoring data, alerts to controller.
Capacity Management- Orchestrates capacity additions and removals without interruption.
Monitoring- Monitors 500+ data points per node and integration with ganglia and nagios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hardware Overview:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proxy Tier- Proxy nodes handles all incoming API requests. Once a proxy server receives a request, it will determine which storage node to connect to, based on the URL of the object. A minimum of two nodes should be deployed in the proxy tier for redundancy. The proxy tier also includes ssl-terminators and authentication services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Storage Tier- When a client uploads data to SwiftStack, the proxy tier will write data in three different availability zones in the storage tier. For incoming read requests, one of the three replicas of the data will be served. Subsequently, each storage node and drive that is added to a Swift cluster will not only provide additional storage capacity, but will also increase the aggregate IO capacity of the cluster as there are more drives available to serve incoming read requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Networking- A typical SwiftStack deployment will have a front-facing ‘access’ network (to run the proxy and authentication services) and a back-end ‘storage’ network.  As there are three copies of each object, an incoming write is sent to three storage nodes. Therefore network capacity for writes needs to be considered in proportion to overall workload.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommended System Requirement:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proxy Tier- Typically, Proxy servers are 1U systems with a minimum of 12 GB RAM. For small SwiftStack clusters, the storage services and proxy services can run on the same physical nodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Storage Tier- Storage nodes are typically higher ­density 2U, 3U or 4U nodes with 12-­‐36 SATA disks each. A good rule of thumb is approximately 1 GB of RAM for each TB of Disk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drives- 2TB or 3TB 7200 RPM SATA drives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Networking- Storage nodes can be provisioned with 1GbE (single gigabit) or 10GbE network interface depending on expected workload and desired performance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NexentaStor</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/NexentaStor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/NexentaStor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nexenta – NexentaStor:  delivers high-performance, ultra-scalable, cloud- and virtualization-optimized storage solutions. Nexenta supplies the software. You leverage your hardware. Does not provide object storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Features&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delivers built-proof data integrity and unlimited scalability for Big Data- and Cloud-optimized storage solutions. Nexenta’s OpenStorage platform allows for a broader range of virtualization and cloud-computing services at a much lower cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High-Availability Clustering.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unlimited Snapshots &amp;amp; Clones:&lt;/strong&gt; NexentaStor uses copy on write (COW), this means live data is never overwritten; instead, it writes data to a new block before changing the data pointers and committing the write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inherent Virtualization&lt;/strong&gt; – NexentaStor supports all the mainstream virtualization vendors; Microsoft Hyper-V, Citrix Xen and VMware vSphere.
Uses ZFS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommended system Requirement for NexentaStor Community Edition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;64 bit processor (32 bit not recommended for production).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 GB RAM minimum for evaluation (recommend 4 to 8 GB), Production use 8 GB minimum plus 1 GB per 1 TB raw disk space minimum (depending on use-case more may be highly desirable), or 2 GB per 1 TB raw for high-end performance deployments. If planning to use deduplication, please contact for sizing assistance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 identical relatively small disks for high-availability system folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additional drives/storage for data volumes&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding about EMC Vipr- All in One</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/EMC-Vipr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/EMC-Vipr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EMC ViPR will purely provide the Control Plane. It discovers storage, creates virtual storage pools, and provisions those pools to the application. Only by separating the data center from its underlying hardware can IT truly deliver resources as customizable, on-demand services. ViPR is able to support IT services in a heterogeneous storage environment while retaining and extending the value of underlying arrays. It perform functions like “in-place” analytics. Abstracting, pooling and automating the infrastructure. It supports open API including Amazon Simple storage service (S3), Open stack Swift &amp;amp; Atmos to completely free data and applications from storage dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managing both storage infrastructure (called the Control Plane) and the data stored within that infrastructure (called the Data Plane).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decoupling the Control Plane from the Data Plane, allowing the use of both together — or enabling customers to use only the Control Plane to manage the underlying intelligence of the storage arrays through policy-based automation. This is a radical departure from prior attempts to virtualize storage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Offering the ability to view objects as files and provides file access performance without the latency inherent to object storage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Providing the capability to be implemented entirely in software and will run against EMC, non-EMC and commodity hardware.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/EMC-Vipr.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;EMC Vipr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Software Defined Storage</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/What-is-Software-Defined-Storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/What-is-Software-Defined-Storage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The concept behind software-defined storage seems very appealing: a single point of data services, like volume management and snapshots, form a single console while using &lt;strong&gt;practically anyone’s disk hardware.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a pillar in the SDDC stack, Software Defined Storage (SDS) pools hardware storage resources and allows them to be programmatically defined in software. All the programming that controls storage-related tasks exists solely in software. The software could exist on a server or could be part of an operating system (OS) or a hypervisor. Provides flexible management at a much more granular level. Deployed Provision through S/W.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SDS forms a part of a broader software-defined data center (SDDC) concept wherein all the virtualized storage, server, networking and security resources required by an application can be defined by software and provisioned automatically. This design provides the means for storage services to be deployed on a wide range of hardware spanning vendor optimized to commodity to cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Desktop Virtualization</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/What-is-Desktop-Virtualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/What-is-Desktop-Virtualization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Desktop Virtualization is the concept of isolating an operating system (OS) from the client that is used to access it. It is also known as client virtualization which separates a computer desktop environment from the physical computer. It is used as a new approach to the provisioning, delivery, and management of user desktops in the enterprise. The main principle behind this new approach is leveraging existing and well-proven virtualization technologies to virtualize not only servers but also user desktops (the workstations). The resulting “virtualized” desktop is stored on a remote central server, instead of on the local storage of remote client; thus, when users work from their remote desktop client, all of the programs, applications, processes and data used are kept and run centrally, allowing users to access their desktops on any capable device, such as a traditional personal computer, notebook computer, smart phone, or thin client. Users may be geographically scattered, but all must be connected to the central machine by a local area network, a wide area network, or the public Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Desktop Virtualization replaces the traditional model where users run all the applications and store data on their desktop services. Instead the whole environment of the desktop experience would be executed in the data center servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/Desktop-Virtualization.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Desktop-Virtualization.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices while going for Storage Virtualization</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Best-Practices-Storage-Virtualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Best-Practices-Storage-Virtualization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set your scope and objectives.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Begin the vendor selection process with specific goals and objectives. We must fully understand what we want to achieve or overcome with storage virtualization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arrange Proper Staff Training&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Address skill gaps so we can properly asses different virtualization approaches. Storage virtualization requires specific training and knowledge, so it’s necessary to asses current IT staff for skills and identify potential knowledge gaps. Also consider vendor specific training once finalized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leverage Storage Resource Management (SRM)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Properly instrumenting SRM tools providing full discovery and visibility of virtual, logic and physical storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Establish Storage Management Standards&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reduce costs associated with managing multiple site management. When you establish storage management standards including standard LUN sizes and naming conventions—you can more easily interchange similar storage subsystems, reducing complicated planning exercises. Standard configurations simplify both production environment planning and disaster recovery site recovery planning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implement Service Maintenance Best Practices&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accurately calculate capital and operational expenses for applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement Storage Virtualization</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Implement-Storage-Virtualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Implement-Storage-Virtualization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why do we need to implement Storage Virtualization?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increasing Storage Demands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Too long to do backup and restore.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limited Space in Data Center.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Need to improve DR capabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Approach for implementation of Storage Virtualization?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host Based:&lt;/strong&gt;  Physical drives are handled by traditional device driver, while a software layer above device driver intercepts I/O requests, looks up metadata and redirects I/O.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple to design and code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports any storage type.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improves storage utilization without thin provisioning restrictions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replication and data migration only possible locally to that host.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Traditional data recovery following a server disk crash is impossible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Storage utilization optimized only on per host basis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Network Based:&lt;/strong&gt;  Storage virtualization is viewed as a network-based device using fibre channel networks connected as SAN. A fibre channel switch which is in between the host and storage will virtualize all requests. Interestingly operating system on the host doesn’t know it’s happening as it this method doesn’t rely on operating system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple Management Interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replication services across heterogeneous devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Difficult to implement fast metadata updates in switches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Out-of-band requires specific host based software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In-band adds latency to I/O.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implementation of Network based&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Appliance Based:&lt;/strong&gt; an appliance residing between client and storage array implements storage virtualization layer and becomes new storage target. When the data is sent to appliance via client storage virtualization features can be enabled such as snapshot, thin provisioning and data replication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Versatility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cost&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Switch Based:&lt;/strong&gt; an application that resides in server connected to fibre channel SAN switch. Though it sits in between host and storage but it may use different techniques for metadata mapping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Faster Speed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expensive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lacks features such as thin provisioning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Storage Device Based:&lt;/strong&gt; the primary storage controller allows direct attachment of other storage controllers and provides virtualization services. It will provide pooling and metadata management services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No additional hardware or infrastructure requirement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provides most of the benefits of storage virtualization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does not add latency to individual I/O.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Storage utilization optimized only across the connected controllers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replication and data migration only possible across the connected controllers and same vendors device for long distance support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Array Based:&lt;/strong&gt; storage virtualization layer lives entirely within storage array.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Challenges  of Storage Virtualization</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Challenges-Storage-Virtualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Challenges-Storage-Virtualization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Storage Architecture becomes  much more complicated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More complication may lead to troubleshooting problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Problem determination and fault isolation can become complex.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arise of situations in which physical storage resources are overcommitted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backing out of failed implementation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interoperability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Management of Meta Data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Higher Latency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefits of Storage Virtualization</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Benefits-Storage-Virtualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Benefits-Storage-Virtualization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved Storage Management in an IT environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better availability and estimation of downtime required with automated management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to migrate data while retaining  I/O access (Non disruptive data migration).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce the number of SAN devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decrease in Power consumed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time Saving.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ease in Data Replication.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy backup, archiving and recovery tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expansion of Storage Capacity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy Updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to increase Storage Volume Size in real time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increased loading and backup speed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Storage Virtualization</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/What-is-Storage-Virtualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/What-is-Storage-Virtualization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is the abstraction of physical media (hard disks or solid state drives etc) from the attaching servers which treats the storage as a single logical entity without regard to the hierarchy of physical media that is involved. Storage virtualization means adding an abstraction layer of software that hides the physical devices from the user and allows all devices to be managed as a single pool.
It adds a new layer of software or hardware in between the storage systems and servers so that the applications would not require to know to which logical drive, partitions or storage subsystems the data resides in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within the context of a storage system, there are two primary types of virtualization that can occur:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Block virtualization&lt;/strong&gt; used in this context refers to the abstraction (separation) of logical storage (partition) from physical storage so that it may be accessed without regard to physical storage or heterogeneous structure. This separation allows the administrators of the storage system greater flexibility in how they manage storage for end users. The act of applying virtualization , to one or more block based (storage) services for the purpose of providing a new aggregated, higher level, richer, simpler, secure, etc., block service to clients. Block virtualization functions can be nested. A disk drive, RAID system or volume manager all perform some form of block address to (different) block address mapping or aggregation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;File virtualization&lt;/strong&gt; addresses the NAS challenges by eliminating the dependencies between the data accessed at the file level and the location where the files are physically stored. This provides opportunities to optimize storage use and server consolidation and to perform non-disruptive file migrations. File virtualization is the creation of an abstraction layer between file servers and the clients that access those file servers. Once deployed, the file virtualization layer manages files and file systems across servers, allowing administrators to present clients with one logical file mount for all servers&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding PaaS</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/PAAS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/PAAS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Platform as a Service (PaaS) is a way to rent hardware, operating systems, storage and network capacity over the Internet. The service delivery model allows the customer to rent virtualized servers and associated services for running existing applications or developing and testing new ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PaaS provides complete stack of development tools which are accessed by developers via web browser to create enterprise level applications, without installing anything besides a web browser on their computers, and deploying these over the complex &amp;amp; heterogeneous infrastructure without any specific skills required. PaaS offerings facilitate the deployment of applications without the cost and complexity of buying and managing the underlying hardware and software and provisioning hosting capabilities, providing all of the facilities required to support the complete life cycle of building and delivering web applications and services entirely available from the Internet. PaaS offerings may include facilities for application design, application development, testing, deployment and hosting as well as application services such as team collaboration, web service integration and marshaling, database integration, security, scalability, storage, persistence, state management, application versioning, application instrumentation and developer community facilitation. These services may be provisioned as an integrated solution over the web.
At a high-level, a PaaS helps organizations, specifically developers, realize the benefits of cloud computing by providing a fast and scalable way to host applications in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technically, a PaaS is an Application Platform comprised of an operating system, middleware and other software that allows applications to run on the cloud with much of the management, security, scaling and other stack related headaches abstracted away. This allows you to focus on two things: customers and developing your application. Let the PaaS deal with system administration details like setting up servers or VMs, installing libraries or frameworks, configuring testing tools, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Traditional Model:&lt;/strong&gt;
Building and running on-premise applications has always been complex, expensive, and risky. Each application required hardware, an operating system, a database, middleware, Web servers, and other software. Once the stack was assembled, a team of developers had to navigate complex programming models like J2EE and .NET. A team of network, database, and system management experts was needed to keep everything up and running. Inevitably, a business requirement would require a change to the application, which would then kick off a lengthy development, test, and redeployment cycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Large companies often needed specialized facilities to house their data centers. Enormous amounts of electricity also were needed to power the servers as well as the systems to keep them cool. Finally, a failover site was needed to mirror the data center so information could be replicated in case of a disaster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The New Model:&lt;/strong&gt;
PaaS provides the entire infrastructure needed to run applications over the Internet. It is delivered in the same way as a utility like electricity or water. Users simply “tap in” and take what they need without worrying about the complexity behind the scenes. And like a utility, PaaS is based on a metering or subscription model so users only pay for what they use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With PaaS, ISVs and corporate IT departments can focus on innovation instead of complex infrastructure. By leveraging the PaaS, organizations can redirect a significant portion of their budgets from “keeping the lights on” to creating applications that provide real business value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This model is driving a new era of mass innovation. For the first time, developers around the world can access unlimited computing power. Now, anyone with an Internet connection can build powerful applications and easily deploy them to users wherever they’re located&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefits Of Cloud Computing</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Computing-Benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Computing-Benefits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accelerates your business by providing limitless scalability and transforming ideas with a greater speed into marketable services and products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brings powerful IT resources to the world. Organizations across the globe can access information technologies which were earlier out of reach, computing infrastructure and world class applications are available without considerable investment up front.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unlocks revenue potential and makes new business models available for any business.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Companies can now collaborate more efficiently to drive business value and innovations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud reduces operating risks as well as improves information management. Protects sensitive information and simplifies disaster recovery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud transforms the economics of the industry from capital driven to pay-as you go. Costs are metered according to the requirements and usage. SLA guarantees the capabilities when you need them. There is greater utilization of the underlying infrastructure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The core advantage of cloud computing is its ability to access high performance computing systems on the basis of sharing and time model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use of standard technology is encouraged and facilitated while delivering the latest technology and with full optimization of resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Things To Look For In Your Cloud Service Provider</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Service-Provider/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Service-Provider/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The cloud computing market is exploding with a large number of new entrants. If you are shopping around for a cloud service provider (CSP), here are ten things you should keep in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Expertise&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A cloud computing service is not a commodity: it is not as simple as providing you with a computer in a server farm. It requires a lot of technical expertise to set up the right system that guarantees security for your data and lets you run your business without interruption. Thus, the first thing you have to look in your CSP is the quality of their team and their technical prowess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trust&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are going to migrate your sensitive enterprise data to a third-party server. You really need to be able to trust that organization. Interview their team and see if they are the people with whom you can trust your confidential corporate information. Ask for references and testimonials. Research the vendor thoroughly before trusting them with your data. Also, look for their industry memberships and accreditations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uptime guarantees&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can you afford to have your server down for hours in the middle of the week? If not, ask for uptime guarantees from CSPs. Ask their existing customers about previous outages, and how soon the vendor had the services restored. Anything more than 1 hour’s downtime/month is unacceptable for most businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools available&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does the CSP have a good tool set to help you with analytics, data management, security, etc? A good tool set provided by the CSP can help you cut the costs of your IT operations team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ease of migration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will it be easy to migrate your data and applications to the cloud? Migration is one of the biggest pain-points for enterprises moving to the cloud, so check if your CSP provides tools and support to make this process less painful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance guarantees&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as uptimes are important, so are performance metrics. Ask the CSP about the servers they are using, the disc access speeds, the processor types, network bandwidth and availability of SSDs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customer Support&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are going to trust your corporate IT infrastructure with a third party. What if your server crashes at the start of the day due to a malfunctioning app? Are you sure you can get it fixed ASAP? Customer support is critical, and it is important that the vendor provides you 24-hour technical support, at least on weekdays. If the support is poor, you can expect to spend a lot of money on your in-house IT team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How serious are they about Security?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security should be a top priority for your CSP. Ask about the steps they take to ensure the security of your data and applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Third-party compliance audits&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have the CSP had their service audited by third-party compliance teams to back up their claims? The industry body, the International Association of Managed Service Providers (MSP Alliance), has a certification standard (UCS) that is used to certify CSPs. Check if your CSP is accredited by it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, it is all about the cost. Check for all the fees (one-time fees, monthly fees, usage fees, etc.) and make sure they are clearly spelled out in the contract.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
