<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title> on Blog </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/tags/nexentastor/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>NexentaStor</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/NexentaStor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/NexentaStor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nexenta – NexentaStor:  delivers high-performance, ultra-scalable, cloud- and virtualization-optimized storage solutions. Nexenta supplies the software. You leverage your hardware. Does not provide object storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Features&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delivers built-proof data integrity and unlimited scalability for Big Data- and Cloud-optimized storage solutions. Nexenta’s OpenStorage platform allows for a broader range of virtualization and cloud-computing services at a much lower cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High-Availability Clustering.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unlimited Snapshots &amp;amp; Clones:&lt;/strong&gt; NexentaStor uses copy on write (COW), this means live data is never overwritten; instead, it writes data to a new block before changing the data pointers and committing the write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inherent Virtualization&lt;/strong&gt; – NexentaStor supports all the mainstream virtualization vendors; Microsoft Hyper-V, Citrix Xen and VMware vSphere.
Uses ZFS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommended system Requirement for NexentaStor Community Edition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;64 bit processor (32 bit not recommended for production).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 GB RAM minimum for evaluation (recommend 4 to 8 GB), Production use 8 GB minimum plus 1 GB per 1 TB raw disk space minimum (depending on use-case more may be highly desirable), or 2 GB per 1 TB raw for high-end performance deployments. If planning to use deduplication, please contact for sizing assistance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 identical relatively small disks for high-availability system folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additional drives/storage for data volumes&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
