<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Sds on Blog </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/tags/sds/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
    
    <updated>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>ScaleIOFeatures</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/ScaleIOFeatures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/ScaleIOFeatures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ScaleIO ECS is a software-only solution that uses application hosts’ local disks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Features:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simplified operation&lt;/strong&gt;- ECS enables IT administrator to manage the entire data center stack.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avoid capacity planning&lt;/strong&gt;- ECS is elastic, enabling you to add, move, remove servers and capacity during I/O operations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-healing&lt;/strong&gt;- It rebalances whenever capacity and/or servers are added.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dynamic performance allocation&lt;/strong&gt;- It provides dynamic allocation based on applications’ needs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Freedom of choice through hardware vendor lock-in elimination.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JedaNetwork</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/JedaNetwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/JedaNetwork/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jeda Networks game changing intelligent software product called the Fabric Network Controller (FNC) abstracts the complexity of a storage network into a software controller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Jeda FNC creates a high performance “storage network overlay” on top of an Ethernet fabric. This Software Defined Storage Network (SDSN) transforms the Ethernet fabric into a powerful and agile storage networking fabric. SDSNs solve the limitations of a fixed and rigid physical storage network—namely scalability, high cost, high complexity, and lack of agility&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Features:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maximize Performance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cut Management Costs-&lt;/strong&gt; mapping your SAN requirements to the physical Ethernet network&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No Hardware Lock-In&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The FNC has been successfully integrated with a number of multi-vendor 10Gb, 40Gb and 100 Gb Data Center Ethernet switches and as FNC is independent of the network hardware the FNC is software, it is network and access speed agnostic, so as speeds migrate to 100Gbs and beyond, the FNC will continue to work within these leaps of performance., it is 10, 40 and 100Gb Ethernet ready today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding about EMC Vipr- All in One</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/EMC-Vipr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/EMC-Vipr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EMC ViPR will purely provide the Control Plane. It discovers storage, creates virtual storage pools, and provisions those pools to the application. Only by separating the data center from its underlying hardware can IT truly deliver resources as customizable, on-demand services. ViPR is able to support IT services in a heterogeneous storage environment while retaining and extending the value of underlying arrays. It perform functions like “in-place” analytics. Abstracting, pooling and automating the infrastructure. It supports open API including Amazon Simple storage service (S3), Open stack Swift &amp;amp; Atmos to completely free data and applications from storage dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managing both storage infrastructure (called the Control Plane) and the data stored within that infrastructure (called the Data Plane).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decoupling the Control Plane from the Data Plane, allowing the use of both together — or enabling customers to use only the Control Plane to manage the underlying intelligence of the storage arrays through policy-based automation. This is a radical departure from prior attempts to virtualize storage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Offering the ability to view objects as files and provides file access performance without the latency inherent to object storage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Providing the capability to be implemented entirely in software and will run against EMC, non-EMC and commodity hardware.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/EMC-Vipr.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;EMC Vipr&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Software Defined Storage</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/What-is-Software-Defined-Storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/What-is-Software-Defined-Storage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The concept behind software-defined storage seems very appealing: a single point of data services, like volume management and snapshots, form a single console while using &lt;strong&gt;practically anyone’s disk hardware.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a pillar in the SDDC stack, Software Defined Storage (SDS) pools hardware storage resources and allows them to be programmatically defined in software. All the programming that controls storage-related tasks exists solely in software. The software could exist on a server or could be part of an operating system (OS) or a hypervisor. Provides flexible management at a much more granular level. Deployed Provision through S/W.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SDS forms a part of a broader software-defined data center (SDDC) concept wherein all the virtualized storage, server, networking and security resources required by an application can be defined by software and provisioned automatically. This design provides the means for storage services to be deployed on a wide range of hardware spanning vendor optimized to commodity to cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
