<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Cloud Computing on Blog </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/categories/cloud-computing/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
    
    <updated>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>A $136-million storage idea: Hitesh Chellani and Anand Babu Periasamy launch cloud computing start-up</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Gluster-Startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Gluster-Startup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2005, when Hitesh Chellani and Anand Babu Periasamy decided to start their own cloud computing start-up, there weren’t too many believers to cheer them. The duo planned to build technology that would store everything that’s ever been filmed, taped, photographed, recorded, written or spoken – an idea so audacious that it was dismissed as a pipe dream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After several meetings at the local Starbucks in Fremont California, the two entrepreneurs launched Gluster with an angel investment of $200,000 from Silicon Valley entrepreneur and investor Anil Godhwani.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the money, few people believed that the two friends could turn this investment into a business that generates many millions of dollars in less than five years. Gluster was started inside Chellani’s home, with his daughter’s bedroom serving as the office and data centre occupied with noisy servers. So successful were they at chasing that dream that in just five years (2011), Red Hat, the world’s leading provider of open source solutions, acquired Gluster for approximately Rs 667 crore ($136 million) in an all-cash deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A lot of people told us what we were doing was impossible and we were crazy. But great ideas are always controversial in the beginning,” said AB Periasamy. The acquisition by Red Hat came through because the start-up had built an open-source storage platform for working with large amounts of data (terabytes, all the way up to petabytes and brontobytes) that ties together everything from the operating system layer to the file system and management interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We are offering this technology to our customers for the first time,” said Brian Stevens, CTO and vice-president, worldwide engineering, Red Hat. The story of Chellani and Periasamy might be common in the US. But in India, where the start-up set up its development centre, this was an uncommon tale of earlystage success. The two are firstgeneration entrepreneurs who did not come from a business family background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A computer engineer graduate from Annamalai University, Periasamy hails from Tharamangalam, a town in Salem district of Tamil Nadu. His father passed away when he was still in school. Faced with financial constraints, his mother had to mortgage the house to help him finish studies. Chellani, an electronics engineer, spent the first two decades of his life in Mumbai where his family of four lived in a 600 sqft apartment. His father had migrated from Pakistan during the partition and gone through a couple of unsuccessful businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beginning his career as a software engineer for Tata Unisys in India, Chellani worked for a while in Dubai to finance his way to a Master’s Degree in the US. Chellani met Periasamy there, while working together at California Digital and were part of the team that built the ‘Thunder’ supercomputer for Lawrence Livermore National Lab. When ‘Thunder’ was put into production in 2004, it was the second-fastest supercomputer in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once they joined forces to launch Gluster the duo battled disbelief until they landed their first customer order with Petroleos de Venezuela, the Venezuelan national oil company. Gluster soon expanded its services by selling opensource storage solutions to customers such as UK defence major BAE Systems, Stanford University, Deutsche Bank and the administrative office of the US courts. To become a significant storage player, Gluster needed serious funding. Just prior to securing first round of funding, the company had just $25,000 in the bank and it had to pay salary to 13 people. “But we did not lose hope” said Chellani.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Computing: What It Is and What It Can Do for You-Introduction</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Computing-Intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/Cloud-Computing-Intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cloud computing is one of the latest computer and business industry buzz words. It joins the ranks of virtualization, grid computing, and clustering, among others, in the IT industry. The problem is that, depending on your point of view, the definition of cloud computing can be quite different. Depending on your perspective, you could look at it from a business point of view or an application point of view, as well as others. This has created confusion on the definition and a fuzzy view as to what cloud computing is or even does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term cloud computing is overused and ill-defined, which has led many IT professionals and management to make assumptions as to what cloud computing does and how their companies can best utilize it. The IT Industry is not making it easier for their customers by offering many different definitions and products that only create confusion. This confusion is what the IT vendors are utilizing to create many different products and call them “cloud products.” Examples of this behavior can be seen by watching television ads that are being broadcast to everyone, not just IT professionals and management. One large IT company defines cloud computing in a way that only a person with a PhD. in linguistics and computer science could understand, but the ad tells you they are making a simple definition, and if you do not understand their definition then call up their professional services to “help” your company take advantage of cloud computing. This ad, as well as other marketing, makes the idea so complex that no one understands it, and this only makes cloud computing more of a “riddle wrapped in an enigma.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cloud is a great marketing term, with lots of hype behind it. This white paper will define cloud computing using a commonly accepted definition to get past the hype. Then we will discuss the different types of cloud computing, which also have added to the confusion as to what cloud computing is and does. We will end with ideas on how you can begin to implement the cloud in your environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term cloud, which is a familiar computer cliché that every computer networking professional has used as the “public internet” in a network design at one time or another, is a great place to start. The internet cloud is drawn into the network design as the part of the network that is not controlled by the company. It represents the unknown path to send data or information between the company and the customer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the IT professional, this is a well-understood concept and has been an acceptable practice for many years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, the internet cloud design has been shown to management over the years, and they also have a comfort level with the design and the concept. Now IT professionals do have a common knowledge of the internet cloud; however, if you combine cloud with computing, the definition becomes fuzzy, and there is no single acceptable meaning. If the concept comes up in a meeting, it begins to remind you of the story of the Emperor who has no clothes. No one wants to admit that they do not know exactly what cloud computing is, and this is why, many years ago, the industry developed Request For Comments (RFC). The RFCs were designed to standardize computer concepts. By standardizing, computers and the Internet were able to grow quickly, because companies had to abide by the RFC. This standardization made it easy for the producer and the consumer to avoid confusion on what was being produced and consumed. However, there are no RFCs for cloud computing, and this creates confusion as to what should or must be done to implement it. Without standardization, the producer and consumer are left to write their own rules and make their own definitions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Cloud Computing?</title>
      <link>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/What-Is-Cloud-Computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Yuvraj Gupta</author>
      <guid>http://guptayuvraj.github.io/post/What-Is-Cloud-Computing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cloud computing is a general term for anything that involves delivering hosted services over the Internet. These services are broadly divided into three categories: Infrastructure-as-a-Service (IaaS), Platform-as-a-Service (PaaS) and Software-as-a-Service (SaaS). The name cloud computing was inspired by the cloud symbol that’s often used to represent the Internet in flowcharts and diagrams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A cloud service has three distinct characteristics that differentiate it from traditional hosting. It is sold on demand, typically by the minute or the hour; it is elastic — a user can have as much or as little of a service as they want at any given time; and the service is fully managed by the provider (the consumer needs nothing but a personal computer and Internet access). Significant innovations in virtualization and distributed computing, as well as improved access to high-speed Internet and a weak economy, have accelerated interest in cloud computing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A cloud can be private or public. A public cloud sells services to anyone on the Internet. (Currently, Amazon Web Services is the largest public cloud provider.) A private cloud is a proprietary network or a data center that supplies hosted services to a limited number of people. When a service provider uses public cloud resources to create their private cloud, the result is called a virtual private cloud. Private or public, the goal of cloud computing is to provide easy, scalable access to computing resources and IT services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Infrastructure-as-a-Service like Amazon Web Services provides virtual server instance API) to start, stop, access and configure their virtual servers and storage. In the enterprise, cloud computing allows a company to pay for only as much capacity as is needed, and bring more online as soon as required. Because this pay-for-what-you-use model resembles the way electricity, fuel and water are consumed, it’s sometimes referred to as utility computing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Platform-as-a-service in the cloud is defined as a set of software and product development tools hosted on the provider’s infrastructure. Developers create applications on the provider’s platform over the Internet. PaaS providers may use APIs, website portals or gateway software installed on the customer’s computer. Force.com, (an outgrowth of Salesforce.com) and GoogleApps are examples of PaaS. Developers need to know that currently, there are not standards for interoperability or data portability in the cloud. Some providers will not allow software created by their customers to be moved off the provider’s platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the software-as-a-service cloud model, the vendor supplies the hardware infrastructure, the software product and interacts with the user through a front-end portal. SaaS is a very broad market. Services can be anything from Web-based email to inventory control and database processing. Because the service provider hosts both the application and the data, the end user is free to use the service from anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
